A surprising amount of the things
you see in nature are poisonous.
One might simply make you sick to
your stomach, or slightly numb...
But combining them together
and refining the result
will make a poison that can
kill even a Red Grizzly.
Alchemy's scary...
I know I said I'd help with
your experiments, but...
Isn't that going to kill me?
Well? Need an antidote spell?
I'm fine. It just tasted terrible.
Undead
Adventurer
You may be the first person in history
who was able to drink that poison
and say how it tastes, Rentt.
As I thought, no poison will work on you.
But for some reason, healing
herbs and potions do.
Your body's quite handy.
Wait, do you still not feel the
need for sleep, even as a ghast?
I don't.
I barely need to sleep at all.
I'm jealous.
What about your appetite?
It's small, but I do feel a desire
for human flesh and blood.
More poison?
Open it.
Blood!
It's my blood.
I've cast preservation magic on the vial.
You may feel reluctant
to ingest human blood,
but you should ingest it at regular
intervals to keep yourself from losing control.
All right.
It's delicious!
You only need one drop?
That's plenty. The thirst is gone.
I'll make it last.
I'm going to head out.
You get some rest, Lorraine.
The labyrinth?
I'm heading to the labyrinth,
yes, but first, the guild.
The guild?
I'm going to take a job.
You're going to need to show Rentt Faina's
adventurer ID if you want
a job from the guild.
If you bring it out looking like that,
the whole guild will be in an uproar.
You think?
Sure, I look different.
But I'm just a Bronze-class adventurer.
Nobody will care.
Listen, Rentt. You're one of
many Bronze adventurers, yes.
But the guild really liked you.
You did everything from
helping out new adventurers
to taking jobs nobody else would take.
Those were just random little jobs.
Don't be so hard on yourself.
There was talk of recruiting
you to work for the guild.
No way.
I don't know anything about that.
Maybe if I were a really talented
adventurer, but I'm not...
They probably found it hard
to bring the subject up,
since you showed no signs of retiring.
How do you know?
Even I know some people at the guild.
I'm grateful they thought that.
But I'm not going to retire,
or work at the guild.
That's what we all assumed.
Now, let's think about this.
You need to pass a test to go up a rank.
And to take that test, you
need to prove yourself.
You need to be the one taking the quests.
But if the guild knows that
Rentt Faina is back...
Rentt!
Just be somebody else!
It feels like it's been a long time.
Oh, there's Sheila!
Looks like she's doing well.
Good morning. Is it your first time here?
I want to register as an adventurer.
All right. You'll need to do some paperwork.
I can fill out all of it except your name.
I know how to read and write.
My apologies.
You can leave any parts that
are too hard for you blank.
But if you put down any skills
you have or magic you can use,
we'll be able to give you more jobs.
The last time I filled this
out was 10 years ago.
Back then, I didn't even know
what counted as a "skill,"
and I could only write down my name and age.
Not like now.
But my goal hasn't changed
at all since then.
Rentt, why not register as an
adventurer under another name?
I can't do that! Using two different
names is against the guild rules!
They'll never know.
And even if they do find out,
it won't be a big deal.
Everyone knows Rentt Faina, and they'd have
no end of questions about
how you ended up that way.
But nobody will ask questions
about a wandering adventurer,
no matter how strange they look.
True.
Well, you'll lose what
accomplishments Rentt Faina had,
and you'll have to start over from Iron.
I don't mind.
My goal is...
to become a Mythril-class
adventurer someday. That's all.
Thank you.
Your name is... Rentt Vivier, correct?
What's wrong?
Nothing, just... an adventurer named
Rentt went missing the other day.
She was worried? About somebody like me?
Well, we did know each
other for a long time.
I'm sorry. It just surprised
me that you had the same name.
I see.
By the way, was that Rentt Faina?
Yes, but how did you know?
Lorraine told me.
Are you a relative of hers?
Yes. She's letting me stay with her.
I'd heard that an unusual-looking man
was seen going in and out of her home.
So that was you, huh?
There were rumors about me, huh?
I was so sure it was Rentt Faina.
He seemed so close to her.
All right. This paperwork looks fine.
Give me a minute to finish this up.
I'm glad I said I was a relative.
Lorraine is a young woman.
I need to make sure there aren't
weird rumors about her.
The name "Rentt" is a common
one in every country.
And it's not unusual for an adventurer
to look a little strange.
Now I can start over!
Rentt Vivier!
Oh, yes?
You are now an Iron-class adventurer.
Do your best!
Thank you.
Just... don't get yourself killed.
Thanks.
Goblins?
Ryze, behind you!
Still young...
They sound like children.
A swordsman and a healer.
Given their age, they must be new.
Laura!
Right!
They seem to be working well together.
They'll probably be fine.
I used to always talk to the
new kids, show them around...
But I'd just scare them, looking like this.
Now, then... time to hurry before the
other adventurers find that place.
Information about the labyrinth
is valuable, and worth money.
Especially information about
newly discovered areas.
If I can explore this new area
and report it to the guild,
it'll be a huge accomplishment.
For the Iron-class
adventurer, Rentt Vivier.
Now, let's see what's waiting for me...
That's not an undead...
Somebody was living here?
Inside the labyrinth?
What are you doing?
I'll ask you one more time.
Oh no... this woman's bad news!
I was searching to see if
there was anything here.
I'm an adventurer.
Searching, you say?
Searching...
For something to steal, correct?
Does that mean you're
prepared to die down here?
There are some things even I can't forgive.
I don't want this place disturbed.
So... disappear, please.
Your body...
Does it offend you?
I didn't end up like this
because I wanted to.
I assume so.
But at least it explains how you got here.
It seems I've misunderstood you.
My apologies.
Oh, you're upset, aren't you?
I burnt your clothes.
No, you almost killed me!
In exchange...
I'll offer you this.
It's well-made, and worth more
than what you were wearing.
She said she "misunderstood" me, right?
Does that mean she doesn't
feel like killing me anymore?
I'm sure you understand that
this place is special.
Would you be willing to keep it a secret?
This room is a special place to me.
You mean don't tell the guild?
Yes, that's correct.
Though, actually, no one can enter
this place unless you're with them.
Oh, if you're an adventurer, you wouldn't
want to go home empty-handed, would you?
I'll give you this Acacia Map instead.
I'm sure it will be of use to you.
A map?
It's a magic item that will automatically record
the spaces through which its owner has traveled.
Our trade is now complete, yes?
I'll return you to the entrance, then.
I wish you good health... Though perhaps
that's not the best thing to say to you.
Are you under some kind of curse?
The strangest things keep
happening to you...
I'm not running into them
because I want to...
And that's why I said it was a curse.
Well, an adventurer's job is
going to see strange things.
Anyway, this magic item...
it doesn't seem cursed.
It seems safe to use.
Any idea how to use it?
It didn't react to my magic at all.
You try it, Rentt.
This is the Labyrinth of
the Moon's Reflection.
It really is a map.
Amazing.
What's this mark?
I'm not sure...
"Ryze" and "Laura"...
Those seem to be names, but what is this?
A pair of rookie adventurers.
I met them in the labyrinth.
Then it's showing you the names of the people
in the labyrinth, as well as their positions?
That's handy.
Rentt, this is incredible!
It's a potential national treasure!
I can't believe this...
Can you bring up maps for
the other labyrinths?
I'm not sure...
Other labyrinths...
The Labyrinth of the New Moon, maybe?
It changed!
But it's not complete.
It's not?
It's not.
Actually, she said it would record the
spaces in the labyrinth that I'd traveled.
So it won't display any areas that its
owner, that is, you, haven't been to?
Hey, can you take a look at this robe, too?
I don't want another curse.
It's fine.
You already have it equipped.
If it was cursed, you'd know by now.
From the look of it, it's of good quality.
It is?
Yes. It has extremely
strong magic resistance,
and no blade could pierce it.
You can safely assume it's far
stronger than regular armor.
Maybe I got a better deal
out of this than I thought.
Rentt, that's not what you
need to be thinking about.
Who is this woman who almost killed you?
I don't know.
She was incredibly powerful.
But at my level of strength, all I can say
is that she's stronger than a Gold-class.
I see.
I'm curious about the room you went to, too.
It means somebody has the ability to make
living spaces within the labyrinth.
I'm going back tomorrow.
Even though you were almost killed?
That's brave.
She didn't tell me to never come back.
She just told me not to tell the guild.
You don't know if that's how she sees it.
From what you said, she clearly
wants to be left alone.
Well, I'll go talk to her, at least.
I'm cursed, huh?
What Lorraine said was right.
On the day I found that new area in the
Labyrinth of the Moon's Reflection...
I met the dragon and became undead.
I still can't get this cursed mask off.
Most people would take pity on me.
But... I don't feel that way at all.
I've fought powerful enemies, encountered
many mysteries... and gotten stronger.
That's just what a Mythril-class
adventurer does!
It's not here.
The entrance is gone?
So she doesn't want me coming back?
No, she doesn't want me
coming back right now.
Welcome back.
The client was very happy.
I'm glad to hear that.
Hey, have you heard anything about Rentt?
Nothing, yet.
I see...
Well, maybe he went off to escort
some traveler or something, right?
Tell me if you ever hear something.
Okay.
Rentt, everyone is worried about you.
A lot of people learned how
to be an adventurer from you.
I only learned how to be a real
guild employee thanks to you...
I'm "nice"?
Yes.
I've never seen myself that way...
But well, I'll do anything if
it helps me become Mythril.
Excuse me...
I'm sorry!
I was just thinking about something,
and you startled me...
That's fine... actually...
I want to take this job.
Three bodies' worth of orc flesh?
The deadline's not for a while, but...
Orcs are quite strong. And you'll
need to fight three of them.
I can't recommend that for
an Iron-class adventurer.
I know how strong orcs are.
You'd need to be an average Bronze-class,
no, a fairly strong one.
Then...
Don't worry. I've defeated
orcs before, several times.
I see.
If you've already fought them, then...
The guild will entrust you,
Rentt Vivier, with this job.
I accept.
Just don't do anything risky, okay?
If it gets dangerous, then run away.
Got it?
Yes. I've only got one life, after all.
I understand that.
No...
I think I understand that
better than anyone.
Bronze-class Exam